原视频名：This Year The Space Station Is Getting Its First Major Expansion in a Decade
原作者名：Scott Manley
视频来源：youtu.be/INiagI9MjvU
原视频发布日期：20210309
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
It's been 10 years since the Space Shuttle delivered its last major component to the International Space Station
自从航天飞机将国际空间站的最后一个主要部件送入轨道以来 已经十年了
The Leonardo module was added in February of 2011.
2011年2月添加了列奥纳多舱
The Space Shuttle had been so critical to the construction of the International Space Station
航天飞机对国际空间站的建造非常重要
that its life was actually extended past the original 2010 retirement date that was set by George Bush.
以至于航天飞机项目进行了延寿 超过了乔治·布什总统原定的2010年退休日期
And that was of course in the wake of the Columbia tragedy.
当然那是在哥伦比亚号惨剧之后
But since the Space Shuttle retired, there's been only very limited additions to the space station.
但自从航天飞机退役后 空间站新增的设备很少
This year however we're going to see a series of significant changes to the structure
然而今年 我们将看到一系列重大的结构变化
with a number of new components that will enhance capabilities
带有一些增强国际空间站能力的新组件
keep the space station running and hopefully make life better for everyone that lives there.
可以让空间站的持续运行 并希望可以改善那里居民的生活
So I want to talk about the changes
所以 我想说的是这些变化
the new hardware that is getting added in the coming year.
也就是在未来的一年里会加的新设备
So the biggest change is going to be on the Russian side of the station
那么最大的变化会发生在俄罗斯部分的这一侧
where the long promised Nauka laboratory module is finally scheduled for launch after years of delays.
也就是承诺已久的科学号实验舱终于在推迟多年后计划发射
This will be a full-size module comparable to the Zarya and Zvezda modules.
这将是一个与曙光号功能货舱和星辰号服务舱相当的全尺寸舱段
In fact Nauka apparently began as a backup of Zarya
事实上 科学号显然是作为曙光号的备份研发
and after that was launched successfully they began converting it into its current form.
并在曙光号成功发射后 他们开始将其改造成现在的形式
Now originally the module was planned for launch in 2007
那么原本计划在2007年发射该舱段
but there's been a few delays including several major issues with the fuel and propulsion system.
但发生了一些延误 包括燃料和推进系统的几个主要问题
And that required a complete replacement of all that stuff.
而这就需要把这些东西全部更换掉
At this point it has to actually launch before the end of the year
因此 它必须在今年年底前发射出去
because the warranty is going to expire on a number of systems.
因为很多系统的保修期都快到了
Now it's also known as the Multi-purpose Laboratory Module or MLM.
现在它又被称为多功能实验室舱段或MLM
It's science focused with research stations
它会专注于科学方面 包含研究站
but it also features things like crew quarters, propulsion systems, solar arrays.
但也包含乘员宿舍 推进系统 太阳能电池阵列等等
It also has the european robotic arm developed by ESA
它还有欧空局开发的欧洲机械臂
and an experimental airlock which can be used for science.
和一个可用于科学的实验气闸
The module is currently scheduled for launch in July
该舱目前计划于7月发射
but work has already been done on the station to prepare for its arrival.
但国际空间站上已经为其到来做好了准备
Now the Nauka module is intended to dock in the location where the Pirs module is currently located.
那么 科学号舱段打算停靠在码头号舱段目前所在的位置
That's a small module that sits on the bottom of the station
那是一个位于空间站底部的小型舱段
and it's functioned as the Russian segment's primary airlock since it was installed.
自安装以来 它一直作为空间站俄罗斯部分的主要气闸舱发挥作用
It also has a docking port which you can dock either Progress or Soyuz on it
它也有一个对接口 你可以在上面对接进步号或联盟号飞船
but it's almost always Progress that's docked on there
但几乎都是进步号停靠在那里
because since that's an airlock,
因为那是一个气闸
you can't have people going on EVA when their escape spacecraft is docked to the other side of an airlock.
在人们的逃生飞船停靠在气闸的另一边时 你不能让他们去进行舱外活动(而不安全)
So anyway assuming everything works when the Progress spacecraft that is docked there leaves the station
那么无论如何 假设停靠在那里的进步号飞船离开空间站时 一切都能正常工作
it will bring the old module with it for disposal where it will burn up in the upper atmosphere
它会把旧的舱段带去丢弃 也就是在上层大气中烧毁
and this is sort of a big deal because this is one of the oldest modules on the space station.
这是一件大事 因为这是国际空间站最古老的舱段之一
It's been there since September 2001.
自2001年9月起就在那里了
So it'll be almost 20 years old when it's disposed off.
所以在它被丢弃掉的时候已经快20年了
but this disposal will only happen once they confirm the successful launch of Nauka on a Proton rocket
但只有当他们用质子火箭成功发射科学号舱段后 才会进行丢弃
and the module is checked out in orbit
同时 也需要在轨道上对该舱段进行检查
and assuming of course that the Pirs module detaches cleanly after being docked for 20 years
当然 也假设码头号舱段在对接20年后能干净利落地分离
because you might have some problems with the hardware cold welding in space.
因为你可能还会在太空中遇到冷焊的问题
There's all sorts of unknowns in the that's involved in this.
这里面会遇到各种各样未知的东西
But assuming all that works then yes the module will guide itself in autonomously
但是 假设一切都起作用 那么 是的 舱段将会自主导航
dock onto the station and deploy its solar panels and radiators
与空间站对接 并部署其太阳能电池板和散热器
and it will be a major expansion.
而这将是一个重大的扩展
Once that's docked there's going to be a second module that's slated to follow on later.
一旦对接好了 就会计划跟进第二个舱段
This is the Prichal module which is a spherical hub with six hybrid docking ports around it
这是停泊号舱段 它是一个球形的枢纽 周围有六个混合对接口
and this will increase the opportunities for future expansion of the Russian segment.
而这将增加俄罗斯部分未来扩展的机会
Now they have a plan module called the science and power module which is currently being targeted for 2024
现在他们计划在2024年发射一个叫科学与动力的舱段
but given the delays that we've seen with Nauka I'm not holding my breath.
但考虑到我们已经看到的科学号实验舱的延迟 我不指望它能按时发射
Suffice to say those extra docking ports added by this module should last them for a very long time.
我只想说 这个舱段增加的那些额外的对接口应该能让他们使用很长时间
Anyway on the international side of the station
总之在国际部分这边
there's no single module that can compare to the 20 ton mass of Nauka.
没有任何一个舱段能与20吨重的科学号舱段相比
All of the components have to be shipped up in the trunk of the Dragon cargo spacecraft
所有的组件都要装在货运龙飞船的货舱段里运上去
so they're necessarily small.
所以它们的体积必然很小
Although I guess the Bigelow expandable activity module
虽然我猜测毕格罗的可扩展活动舱段
that showed that with the right hardware you can squeeze big things into small spaces.
表明 只要设备合适 你可以把大东西挤进小空间里
So the first new part is the Bishop airlock
那么第一个新的部件是主教号气闸舱
which actually arrived on a Dragon spacecraft just before christmas.
它实际上是在(2020年)圣诞节前搭乘龙飞船抵达的
It was extracted and it's berthed
它被抽出来并停泊好了
and it's finally been opened by the crew in the last few days.
而这几天终于被乘员打开了
So this airlock is a commercial scientific airlock that can be used to expose experiments to space.
那么这个气闸是一个商业科学气闸舱 可以用来将实验暴露在太空中
And it can also be used to launch cubesats from the station.
也可以用来从空间站发射立方星
See a big part of the science that's done on the space station is
注意到在空间站上进行的大部分科学工作
just exposing materials to the hard vacuum radiation temperature ranges of the vacuum of low earth orbit.
只是将材料暴露在近地轨道的硬真空辐射温度范围内
Just to determine how they react and how they behave over long periods.
只是为了确定它们在长时间内的反应和行为
And this is really important of course if you're developing future hardware for use in space.
如果你要开发以后用于太空中的设备 这一点非常重要
So the airlock was designed built and operated by a company called Nanoracks
那么这个气闸是由一家叫Nanoracks的公司设计建造并运营的
and it's the first major commercial component of the International Space Station.
而这也是国际空间站的第一个主要的商业部件
Although there's been some questions in the last few days
虽然在过去的几天里出现了一些问题
as to the costs of using the station as a commercial entity
关于将空间站作为商业实体使用的费用问题
as apparently there's some language in the recently passed NASA budget
因为显然在最近通过的NASA的预算中产生了一些争议
which stops NASA subsidizing certain commercial operations.
这阻止了NASA对某些商业业务的补贴
I hope that gets sorted out
我希望能解决这个问题
but the airlock itself it's attached to the Tranquility module on the port side berthing adapter
但气闸本身是连接到宁静号舱段侧面的停泊对接口上的
which makes it kind of low profile and hard to find unless where to look at
这让它变得有点低调 很难找到 除非你知道要往哪里看
sort of tucked in on the edge of the station next to the radiators.
就像是藏在空间站边上的散热器旁边
However the other major update on the international section this year will be easy to see.
然而今年国际部分的另一个重大更新将很容易看到
These are the new improved roll-out solar arrays or iROSA.
这些就是新的改进型滚动式太阳能阵列或者说iROSA
There will be six new solar panels attached to the station.
空间站会连接六块新的太阳能电池板
The original solar panels were shipped up to the space station
原来的太阳能电池板被运到空间站
attached to the truss segments with their rotation gimbals and everything.
连接到带有旋转万向节和其他东西的桁架段上
These were inside the Space Shuttle, right.
对吧 这些都是放在航天飞机里(运输上来的)
And with the much more limited capacity of the Dragon's trunk,
而龙飞船的货舱段所拥有的容量就少得多
they're not planning on adding entirely new solar tracking mounts and hardware for the panels.
他们不打算为新太阳能板添加全新的太阳跟踪支架和设备
Instead these are going to be mounted on top of the existing panels in front of them
而是将其安装到现有的面板上方
to take advantage of the existing tracking capabilities.
以利用现有的跟踪功能
That means the new panels will cover some of the old legacy panels.
这意味着新面板将覆盖部分旧的老面板
But because of improvements in technology and the degradation of the panels are already in space
但由于技术的改进 以及旧面板的老化
it still works out to be a significant improvement to the station power generation.
仍然能大大提高空间站的发电量
Like the technology in the new solar cells will get something like 30 percent conversion efficiency
像新的太阳能电池的技术可以达到差不多30%的转换效率
while the existing panels after 20 years only get about 14 percent efficiency.
而现有的面板在使用了20年后只能达到约14%的效率
So overall it works out to be about 20 kilowatts extra per panel or 120 kilowatts when they're all installed
那么总体来说 每块电池板大约可以多出20千瓦 或者说总计能多出120千瓦
and while the station has room for eight they're only using the six
而尽管空间站可以容纳八人 但现在只有六人常驻
because this is a sort of minimum required to maintain existing operations.
因为这是维持现有业务所需的某种最低限度
They have the option to extend at a later date.
(而多余的电力可以让)他们选择在以后增加人手
So there's been some EVAs to install struts and mounting points on the existing panel support structure.
那么 现在已经有一些舱外活动 会在现有的面板支撑结构上安装支柱和支架
Once these are done the panels will be sent up in future cargo Dragon launches.
一旦这些都做完了 这些面板将在未来的货运龙飞船的发射中被送上去
And they'll be attached and then unrolled.
然后它们会被连接起来并展开
So the design is different from the existing solar arrays that power the station.
那么这个设计与现有的为空间站供电的太阳能阵列的不同
The support struts and the panels they both roll flat into rolls
支撑杆和电池板都是平平地卷起来的
and as they're unrolled they sort of spring into a cylinder shape
当它们展开的时候 就会在弹力的作用下变成圆柱形
rolling into these cylinders and making them rigid enough to support the panels in space.
卷成桶形 变得具有足够的刚性 以支持在太空中的面板
The design was actually tested back in 2017.
这个设计其实早在2017年就已经测试过了
They launched a Dragon pulled it out with the robot arm
他们发射了(装有测试版太阳能板)的龙飞船 用机械臂把它拉了出来
rolled out and then watched how it behaved over a week whilst subjecting it to vibration experiments.
展开 然后观察它一周内的表现 同时进行震动实验
And that worked pretty well.
而这一切都进展顺利
However at the end of the test they found they couldn't roll them back up and lock them in place
然而在测试结束时 他们发现无法将其卷起并锁定在正确的位置
for disposal on the Dragon trunk.
这样就无法放在龙飞船的货舱里丢弃
So they instead just had to let the panels go in deployed form
所以他们只能让面板以部署的形式离开
and because they were had such big surface area to mass ratio
因为它们有如此大的表面积与质量比
they actually deorbited in about eight months.
实际上会在8个月内脱离轨道
So from this point on each cargo Dragon is going to carry a pair of these panels on a pallet in the trunk.
那么从现在开始 每艘货运龙飞船的货舱段里的托盘上都会装上一对这样的面板
And they'll be installed.
之后就会被安装上
The canadarm will pull out the pallet and store that in the station.
加拿达臂会把托盘拉出来 存放在空间站里
And then help astronauts on EVAs move these to the position where they fold out unroll
然后在宇航员进行舱外活动时 借助机械臂 将其移到相应位置 然后展开
and get the extra power
然后空间站的发电量就会得到提升
so as of right now there's Dragon flight scheduled for June, August and December.
因此 截至目前 在六月 八月和十二月 有龙飞船的飞行计划
So yeah the installation of these new panels should be finished by early 2022.
那么是的 这些新面板的安装应该在2022年初完成
So this year is going to be a big deal for the station with a lot of changes to the structure.
那么今年对于国际空间站而言会很重要 其结构上会发生很多变化
Probably the biggest set of changes until say 2024
可能到2024年才会有最大的变化
when yes we've got a module on the Russian side potentially
那时俄罗斯部分可能会增加舱段
but also on the international side
而在国际部分
Axiom are intending to start launching the components for their commercial station extension
Axiom打算开始发射其商业空间站扩展段的组件
where they want to have three modules which can be sold to tourists or scientists that need to do stuff in space.
扩展段中包含三个舱段 可以卖给需要在太空中做事情的游客或者科学家
I'm Scott Manley. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manley 切记 注意飞行安全
[Music]
[音乐]